Robert James Sapunarich

Orange County, CA

949-702-3090 | robertsapunarich@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Robert Sapunarich | GitHub: robertsapunarich

Professional Summary

Software engineer experienced in developing APIs and web applications, building features and fixing bugs for industryleading products, and interacting directly with non-technical colleagues and users. Skilled in analyzing problems and developing solutions. Devoted to integrity and excellence.

Experience

W+R Studios — Huntington Beach, CA

June 2016 - Present

Software Engineer

- API and web application development with Ruby, Rails, Elasticsearch, JavaScript (ES6/React), and HTML/CSS.
- Develop GraphQL APIs for single page applications.
- Develop and maintain two versions of the internal Data Services API, while migrating legacy systems to implementing the new version.
- Refactor and develop solutions for high-throughput systems as scaling problems arise.
- Implement new features and add test coverage for legacy codebases.
- Identify and fix bugs for multiple products reported by users, support, and error reporting systems.
- Communicate and interact regularly with non-technical stakeholders, including project managers, sales, support, and users.
- Collaborate with developers, designers, and stakeholders in brainstorming and architecting solutions.

Eagle Industrial Group DBA SafeRacks - Lake Forest, CA **Operations Specialist**

Feb 2012 - May 2016

- Train third-party contractors, accounting team, and customer service associates on new processes during transition to a new CRM application built with Intuit QuickBase.
- Troubleshoot bugs and UX issues during implementation of QuickBase app and provide feedback to VP of Operations and VeilSun development team.

Skills/Tools

Skills:

API development, Web Application Development, REST, GraphQL, Test-Driven Development, Legacy Systems.

Tools:

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript (ES6, React.js, ¡Query), HTML/CSS, Elasticsearch, Unix Environments, Git, PostgreSQL.

Education

The Firehose Project, Online Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp — Boston, MA Sep 2015-Dec 2015

Build web apps using technologies such as Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript.

California Baptist University — Riverside, CA

Graduation Spring 2015

- Bachelor of Arts in English
- GPA 3.73; Magna Cum Laude
- President's Award for Excellence in Writing First Runner-Up 2014 & 2015
- Sigma Tau Delta International English Honor Society
- Presentation at PAMLA's 2014 Conference: "Grace in the Maelstrom: Calvinism in Moby-Dick"